Register of the Marina Daksergof Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Marina Daksergof collection,
1918-1999
2001C46
Daksergof, Marina
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to various members of the Russian aristocracy and to the Russian Civil War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains materials related to the Konno-Egerskii Polk, biographical articles about Grand Duchess Mariia Pavlovna of Russia and Olga Ilyin (Boratynski), as well as the memoirs of M. V. Golitsyn.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russia--Nobility.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russia.; Soviet Union.
Series Description
- Golitsyn, M. V., n.d. (Box 1)
  Typescript
- Dimitry Pavlovich, Grand Duke, 1999. (Box 1)
  Printed matter
- Ilyin (Boratynski), Olga, n.d. (Box 1)
- Mariia Pavlovna, Grand Duchess, 1998-1999. (Box 1)
- Palei, Ol'ga Valerianovna, Kniaginia, n.d. (Box 1)
- Russia. Armiia. Konno-Egerskii Polk, 1918-1922. (Box 1)
  Clippings, correspondence and identity papers
Container List
- GOLITSYN, M. V. Memoirs, n.d. (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
- DIMITRY PAVLOVICH, GRAND DUKE. Incomplete article about him by Grant Menzies entitled "Grand Duke Dimitry Pavlovich," The European Royal History Journal, March-April 1999 (Folder 1: 4)
- ILYIN (BORATYNSKI), OLGA. Article about her by Grant Menzies entitled "A certain vision of truth," n.d., Atlantis Magazine, Volume 1, #1 (Folder 1: 5)
- MARIIA PAVLOVNA, GRAND DUCHESS. Article about her by Grant Menzies entitled "Marisha: Grand Duchess Marie Pavlovna of Russia," The European Royal History Journal, November-December 1998-January-February 1999. (Folder 1: 6)
- PALEI, OL'GA VALERIANOVNA, KNIAGINIA. Article about her by Grant Menzies entitled "Brief Splendor: The Life of Olga, Princess Paley (1865-1929)," n.d., Atlantis Magazine, Volume 1, #2. (Folder 1: 7)
  Incomplete
- RUSSIA. ARMIIA. KONNO-EGERSKII POLK, 1918-1922. (Folder 1: 8)
  Includes correspondence and identity papers of Boris Mikhailovich Daksergof and Colonel Vrashtil'